張 凱鵬 (ZHANG, KAIPENG)

E-mail: kpzhang@ut-vision.org About Me

I am a second-year Ph.D. student in the Graduate School of Information Science and Technology at The University of Tokyo, supervised by Prof. Yoichi Sato. Before coming to UTokyo, I received my M.S. degree in 2018 from National Taiwan University and B.E. degree in 2016 from Donghua University.

I was a researcher in SenseTime and algorithm consultant in ULSee. I also did research internships at Microsoft Research Asia, Tencent AI Lab, and MMLAB of SIAT. My research interest mainly lies in computer vision, machine learning, and focus on face analysis, active learning, and few-shot learning. My works received over 4200 citations and 4000 GitHub Stars. I also won some face analysis competition in CVPR and ICMI.













Edwarting

Education	
Ph.D The University of Tokyo, Japan	04/2019 - 02/2022
Graduate School of Information Science and Technology	
supervised by Prof. Yoichi Sato	
M.S National Taiwan University, Taiwan	09/2016 - 08/2018
Graduate Institute of Networking and Multimedia,	
supervised by Prof. Winston Hsu.	
B.E Donghua University, China	09/2012 - 07/2016
Computer Networking (Excellent Engineer Program)	
Experience	
Tencent AI Lab	09/2020 - 01/2021
Tencent Rhino-Bird Elite Training Program	
Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu	
- Face recognition model architecture	
The University of Tokyo	04/2019 - 03/2022

Ph.D. student & Research assistant (JSPS Fellowship)

Advisor: Prof. Yoichi Sato

- Real-time semantic segmentation. ICRA 2020
- Few-shot learning and active learning

SenseTime Group Ltd.

09/2018 - 03/2019

Researcher

A core team member to build an incremental large-scale face recognition learning system for ShenZhen Security Bureau.

Microsoft Research Asia

01/2018 - 07/2018

Intern

Memtor: Dong Chen

Large-scale face recognition

National Taiwan University

09/2016 - 08/2018

Master student & Research assistant

Advisor: Prof. Winston Hsu

- Face hallucination and recognition. ECCV 2018 & CVPRW 2018
- Virtual try-on shoe. ACCV 2018
- Disguised face recognition in the wild. Rank 1 in Disguised Faces in the Wild Challenge, CVPR 2018.
- Group-level emotion recognition in the wild.

Rank 1 in EmotionW (ICMI Grand Challenge) 2017 and Rank 2 in EmotionW 2018

ULSee Technology Co., Ltd. 10/2016 – 03/2018

Algorithm consultant for real-world face analysis products.

Tencent AI Lab 07/2017 – 09/2017

Intern

Mentor: Dr. Zhifeng Li and Dr. Wei Liu

- Real-time face detection and alignment. ICCV 2017

Multimedia Laboratory, Shenzhen Institutes of Advanced Technology

07/2015 - 08/2016

Visiting student

Advisor: Prof. Zhifeng Li and Prof. Yu Qiao

- Face Recognition.

A discriminative deep feature learning approach (a.k.a Center loss). ECCV 2016 & IJCV

- Face detection and alignment.

A multi-task cascaded convolutional networks for face detection and alignment (a.k.a MTCNN). IEEE SPL.

- Facial attributes recognition.

A deep convolutional neural network-based approach.

Primary contributor: Rank 1st in ChaLearn Looking at People Challenge - Track 2 & 3, CVPR 2016.

Publications (received 4200 citations, Google Scholar)

Regular paper

* indicate equal contribution

- 1. Zhanpeng Zhang, **Kaipeng Zhang**, "FarSee-Net: Real-Time Semantic Segmentation by Efficient Multi-scale Context Aggregation and Feature Space Super-resolution", ICRA 2020.
- Yandong Wen*, Kaipeng Zhang*, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Comprehensive Study on Center Loss for Deep Face Recognition", IJCV 2019
- 3. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Chia-Wen Cheng, Winston Hsu, Yu Qiao, Wei Liu and Tong Zhang, "Super-Identity Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", ECCV 2018.
- 4. Chao-Te Chou, Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee and Winston Hsu, "Pose Invariant Virtual Try-On Shoe with Conditional Image Completion", ACCV 2018.
- 5. Cheng-Han Lee, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Hu Cheng Lee, Chia-Wen Cheng and Winston Hsu, "Attribute Augmented Convolutional Neural Network for Face Hallucination", CVPRW 2018.
- Kaipeng Zhang, Zhanpeng Zhang, Hao Wang, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao and Wei Liu, "Detecting Faces Using Inside Cascaded Contextual CNN", ICCV 2017.
- 7. Yandong Wen, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "A Discriminative Deep Feature Learning Approach for Face Recognition", ECCV 2016. (a.k.a Center Loss)
- 8. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Zhanpeng Zhang, Zhifeng Li and Yu Qiao, "Joint Face Detection and Alignment using Multi-task Cascaded Convolutional Networks", IEEE SPL 2016. (a.k.a MTCNN)

Competition paper

- 1. Guo, Da, Kai Wang, Jianfei Yang, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Xiaojiang Peng, and Yu Qiao, "Exploring Regularizations with Face, Body and Image Cues for Group Cohesion Prediction," ICMI 2019.
- 2. Wang, Kai, Jianfei Yang, Da Guo, **Kaipeng Zhan**g, Xiaojiang Peng, and Yu Qiao, "Bootstrap model ensemble and rank loss for engagement intensity regression," ICMI 2019.
- 3. Kaipeng Zhang, Ya-Liang Chang and Winston Hsu, "Deep Disguised Faces Recognition", CVPRW 2018
- 4. Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Jianfei Yang, Debin Meng, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Cascade Attention Networks for Group Emotion Recognition with Face, Body and Image Cues", ICMI 2018.
- 5. Lianzhi Tan, **Kaipeng Zhang**, Kai Wang, Xiaoxing Zeng, Xiaojiang Peng and Yu Qiao, "Group Emotion Recognition with Individual Facial Emotion CNNs and Global Image Based CNNs", ICMI 2017.
- 6. **Kaipeng Zhang**, Lianzhi Tan, Zhifeng Li, Yu Qiao, "Gender and Smile Classification using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks", CVPRW 2016.

Selected Honors & Awards

Selected Honors & Awards	
JSPS Research Fellowships for Young Scientists	2020
Tencent Rhino-Bird Elite Training Program	2020
Collaborative Research Program, The University of Tokyo	2019
Scholarships from Foundation's Support Fund, The University of Tokyo	2019
MSRA Fellowship Nomination Award	2019
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis, Donghua University	2016
Selected Competitions	
Primary contributor	
Disguised Faces in the Wild Workshop, CVPR 2018, Rank 1st	2018
Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2017 Grand Challenge, Rank 1st	2017
Accessories Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, Rank 1st	2016
Smile and Gender Classification, ChaLearn Looking at People Challenging, CVPR 2016, Rank 1st	2016
Secondary contributor	
Group-based Cohesion Prediction, EmotiW, ICMI 2019 Grand Challenge, Rank 2 nd	2019
Engagement Prediction in the Wild, EmotiW, ICMI 2019 Grand Challenge, Rank 3 rd	2019
Group-level emotion recognition, EmotiW, ICMI 2018 Grand Challenge, Rank 2 nd	2018

Academic Service

Senior Program committee

IJCAI

Reviewer/Program committee

NeurIPS, ICLR, AAAI, ECCV, ICCV, CVPR, ACCV, WACV

TPAMI, TIP, TNNLS, TCSVT, TMM, Neurocomputing, Pattern Recognition, and SPL.